Guide to the Richard Courant Papers MC 150
New York University Archives
- Series I: Files from the Home of Ernst Courant, 1907-1969
  - Subseries B: Subject Files
    - Rockefeller Foundation stipends, 1927-1933 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Runge, Carl--Obituary, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook from Joint Soviet-American Symposium on Partial Differential Equations, circa 1963 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Shipment of belongings, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Springer-Verlag--accounts, 1928-1937, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Springer-Verlag--compensation, 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Springer-Verlag--contracts, 1918-1949, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Springer-Verlag--general (1 of 2), 1951-1955 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Springer-Verlag--general (2 of 2), 1951-1955 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Springer-Verlag--general, 1956-1960 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Springer-Verlag--general, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Springer-Verlag--general, 1961-1966 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Springer-Verlag--general, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Springer-Verlag--general, 1964-1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Springer-Verlag--general, 1967-1971 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Springer-Verlag--general, 1969-1971 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Springer-Verlag--Hanseatic Corp., 1934-1937 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Springer-Verlag--Office of Alien Property claim, 1941-1950 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Springer-Verlag--resignation from board, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Materials detailing Courant and others' resignation from the board of German math journal Zentralblatt für Mathematik, and the potential founding of an American version of the Zentralblatt.
    - Springer-Verlag--taxes, 1934-1935 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Sympathy letters to Nina Courant on professor's passing, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Ueber langsam veraenderliche Wechselstroeme in der Erde und einige Fragen der Geophysik", 1926 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Urysohn Scholarship Fund, 1933-1935 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Viktoria "Restit. S9" (life insurance), 1933-1938, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Wiedergutmachung, undated, [1959] (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Part of a letter detailing Courant’s attempts to get restitution/reparations after WWII. Also includes letter from Herbert Beyer.
    - What is Mathematics?--general, 1962-1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - What is Mathematics?--general, 1962-1970 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - What is Mathematics?--Hungarian edition, 1959-1960 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - What is Mathematics?--Italian edition, 1948-1953, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - What is Mathematics?--Japanese edition, 1954-1960 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - What is Mathematics?--Permissions, 1947-1960 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - What is Mathematics?--Polish edition, 1952-1958 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - What is Mathematics?--Polish edition, 1961-1967 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - What is Mathematics?--Publicity (1 of 2), 1941-1951 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - What is Mathematics?--Publicity (2 of 2), 1941-1951 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - What is Mathematics?--Publishers' bios, 1939-1941 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - What is Mathematics?--Spanish edition, 1945-1960 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - What is Mathematics?--Yugoslavian edition, 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - World War I documents, circa 1918 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Document certifying Courant was wounded in combat
    - J. Wiley and Sons, 1959-1973 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - J. Wiley and Sons, 1959-1973 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Zentralblatt resignation (Transformation Korrespondenz für Andere), 1938, 1941, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Includes correspondence with Neugebauer, Ferdinand Springer, Harald Bohr, R.C. Archibald, Oswald Veblen, Marston Morse, Simon Lefschetz, George Birkhoff, and F.K. Schmidt re: Courant’s resignation from the Zentralblatt für Mathematik, Otto Neugebauer’s appointment at Brown University in 1939, and the potential founding of an American version of the Zentralblatt.
- Series II: Files from the Office of Richard Courant
  - Subseries A: General Files
    - "A" Misc. (1 of 4), 1937-1950 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - "A" Misc. (2 of 4), 1937-1950 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - "A" Misc. (3 of 4), 1937-1950 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "A" Misc. (4 of 4), 1937-1950 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Aaboe, Asger H., 1961-1968 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Adler, Claire Fisher, 1941-1971, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Admin.--Committee on Research Projects and Grants (1 of 2), 1949 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Admin.--Committee on Research Projects and Grants (2 of 2), 1949 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--A up to 1950 incl. (1 of 3), 1937-1944 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--A up to 1950 incl. (2 of 3), 1937-1944 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--A up to 1950 incl. (3 of 3), 1937-1944 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--A, 1952-1971 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--A, 1952-1971 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--B up to 1950 incl. (1 of 2), 1936-1949 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--B up to 1950 incl. (2 of 2), 1936-1949 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--C up to 1950 incl., 1937-1943 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--D up to 1950 incl., 1939-1941, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--E up to 1950 incl., 1938-1941 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--F up to 1950 incl., 1936-1948 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--G up to 1950 incl., 1935-1943 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--H up to 1950 incl., 1938-1941 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--J up to 1950 incl., 1940-1944 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--K up to 1950 incl., 1937-1943 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--L up to 1950 incl., 1936-1949 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--M up to 1950 incl. (1 of 2), 1937-1944 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--M up to 1950 incl. (2 of 2), 1937-1944 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--N up to 1950 incl., 1937-1944 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--O up to 1950 incl., 1943-1945 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--P up to 1950 incl. (1 of 2), 1935-1950 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--P up to 1950 incl. (2 of 2), 1935-1950 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--R up to 1950 incl., 1939-1950 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--R up to 1950 incl., 1939-1950 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--S up to 1950 incl., 1938-1948 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--S up to 1950 incl., 1938-1948 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--T up to 1950 incl., 1947-1950, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
      Telegrams to/from Donald Flanders, Heinrich Behnke, Theodore von Karman, Kurt Reidemeister, Peter Lax, Ferdinand Springer, Wilhelm Magnus, Natascha Artin, Heinz Hopf, Fritz John, Max Dehn, Harald Bohr, J. J. Stoker, Eberhard Hopf, Chandrasekhar, Rudolf Luneburg
    - Admin.--Correspondence--T up to 1950 incl., 1947-1950, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Telegrams to/from Charles DePrima, Rudolf Luneburg, Wolfgang Sternberg, Chandrasekhar, Karl Friedrichs, Otto Neugebauer, J. J. Stoker, Donald Flanders, Carl Siegel, Robert Oppenheimer, Hans Lewy, Peter Lax
    - Admin.--Correspondence--V up to 1950 incl., 1936-1946 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--V up to 1950 incl., 1936-1945 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--W up to 1950 incl., 1936-1943 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Admin.--Correspondence--XYZ up to 1950 incl., 1938, 1944, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Admin.--Defense Courses (1 of 2), 1941-1942, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Admin.--Defense Courses (2 of 2), 1941-1942, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Admin.--Degree Candidates (1 of 2), 1938-1944 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Admin.--Degree Candidates (2 of 2), 1938-1944 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Admin.--DePrima, Dr. Charles, 1940-1943 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Admin.--Engineering, College of (1 of 2), 1937-1944 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Admin.--Engineering, College of (2 of 2), 1937-1944 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Admin.--Engineering, Department of, 1941-1942 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Admin.--Faculty Club, 1934-1940 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Admin.--Library--Math Grad Center, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Admin.--Library--Washington Square, 1937-1949 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Admin.--Miscellaneous Correspondence (1 of 4), 1943-1948 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Admin.--Miscellaneous Correspondence (2 of 4), 1943-1948 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Admin.--Miscellaneous Correspondence (3 of 4), 1943-1948 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Admin.--Miscellaneous Correspondence (4 of 4), 1943-1948 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Admin.--Miss Reeves--Grades and Class Member Lists, 1941-1948 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Admin.--Miss Reeves--Grades and Class Member Lists, 1941-1948 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Admin.--Miss Reeves--Grades and Students, 1940-1947 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Admin.--Miss Reeves--Grades and Students, 1940-1947 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Admin.--Navy Contract, 1946-1948 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Admin.--National Youth Administration (Heild, Snyden, Weintraub), 1938-1942 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Admin.--Purchasing Department Correspondence, 1935-1945 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Admin.--Rent of Space, 1943-1947 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Admin.--Senate, 1945-1948 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Admin.--Procedures Regarding Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Remarks About, 1958 July 15 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Advanced Analysis II: Calculus of Variations, 1937-1938 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Advanced Methods in Applied Mathematics, circa 1941 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Advanced Topics in the Theory of Functions of a Complex Variable, Lectures on (1 of 2), 1939 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Advanced Topics in the Theory of Functions of a Complex Variable, Lectures on (2 of 2), 1939 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Advertising--Courant books, 1964-1965 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Advisory Board of the Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Memo to Members, 1958 December 3 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Advisory Board of the Institute for Mathematical Sciences, Address to, 1953 May 13 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Albert, A.A. (University of Chicago), 1948-1960 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Alexandroff, Paul, 1945-1969 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Alien Property Custodian, 1944-1956 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Alisbah, Orhan, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, circa 1964 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1962-1966, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - American Committee for the Institute for Advanced Study-Europe, Inc., 1964-1968, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - American Committee for the Institute for Advanced Study-Europe, Inc., 1964-1968, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - American Mathematical Society, 1940-1960 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - American Mathematical Society, 1940-1960 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - American Mathematical Society, 1961-1963 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - American Mathematical Society, 1961-1963 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - American Mathematical Society, 1964-1967 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - American Mathematical Society Award, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - American Mathematical Society--committee, 1936-1941 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - American Mathematical Society--committee bulletins, reports, accounts, etc., 1941-1944 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - American Mathematical Society--committee bulletins, reports, accounts, etc., 1941-1944 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - American Mathematical Society--committee bulletins, reports, accounts, etc., 1945-1950 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - American Mathematical Society--committee bulletins, reports, accounts, etc., 1945-1950 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - American Mathematical Society Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - American Mathematical Society Reports, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1961-1971 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - American Physical Society, 1960-1964, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Amerio, Luigi, 1951-1959 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - AMP Report 42.2R: The Force of Impact on a Sphere Striking a Water Surface, 1946 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - AMS and NRC Conference, talk by Courant, 1953 October 23 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Andhra University, India, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Applied Mathematics and Mechanics, Johns Hopkins University, 1957-1959 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Applied Mathematics and Mechanics, Johns Hopkins University, 1953-1956 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Argonne National Laboratory, 1953-1960 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Argonne National Laboratory, 1960-1972 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Armament Research Institute Translation, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Army, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Army Mathematics Research Center, U. of Wisc. (R.E. Langer), 1956-1960 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Army Mathematics Center, NYU Proposal, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Army Office of Ordinance Research Proposals, 1951-1959 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Aronszajin, Nachman, 1950-1957 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Artin, Emil, 1935-1958 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Artin, Natascha Brunswick, 1950-1955, undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Artin, Natascha--European Trip (Diary), 1947 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Asgiersson, Leifur, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Asgiersson, Leifur, "The 'Diversor' Method in the Theory of Cauchy's Problem for Linear Second Order Partial Differential Equations of Hyperbolic Type", undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Asociacion Venezolana Para el Avance de la Ciencia, 1957- 1964 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Associated Universities, Inc., 1952-1957 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Atkinson, F.V. "Orthogonal Polynomials in N Dimensions", 1958 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Atoms for Peace Awards, 1957-1960 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Atomic Energy Commission, 1946-1960 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Atomic Energy Commission Access Permit Etc. General File, 1959-1971 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Atomic Energy Commission Foreign Travel Reports, 1952-1960 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Atomic Energy Commission--General File, 1956-1957 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Atomic Energy Commission--General File, 1957-1958 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - "Aufgaben zur Funktionentheorie", 1930 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Anzahl Relationen fur Flachpunkte, undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Aydelotte, Frank, 1941-1947 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - "B" Misc., 1943-1960 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - "B" Misc., 1943-1960 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - "B" Misc., 1961-1971 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - "B" Misc., 1961-1971 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Baade, Fritz, 1950-1956 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Bailyn, Paul, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Balaban-Alterman, Zipora, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Balke, Siegfried, 1962 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Bechert, Karl, 1948-1965 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Behnert, Constantin N., 1948-1951 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Behnke, Heinrich, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Behnke, Heinrich, 1947-1952 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Behnke, Heinrich, 1948-1950 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Behnke, Heinrich, 1951 July-1956 November (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Behnke, Heinrich, 1957-1960 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Behnke, Heinrich, 1963-1969 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Bell Telephone Labs--Course Syllabi, 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Bell Telephone Labs--Course Syllabi, 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Bell Telephone Labs--General, 1953-1958 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Bell, Winthrop P., 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Bellman, Richard, 1954-1959 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Berkeley Negotiations--Possible Transfer, 1949-1950 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Berkowitz--Jerry and Lori, 1952-1961 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Bernstein, Felix, 1936-1953 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Bers, Lipman, 1954-1971 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Bers, Lipman--Memo re: A New College, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Bertin, David, 1946-1955 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Bethe, Hans A., 1942-1954 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Bibliography--Methods of Mathematical Physics Vol. II, 1961 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Biermann, Ludwig, 1953-1960 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Billikopf, Jacob, 1949-1950 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Biographical Material (1 of 2), 1922-1949 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Biographical Material (2 of 2), 1922-1949 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Biographical Material (1 of 2), 1951-1960 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Biographical Material (2 of 2), 1951-1960 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Biographical Material, 1964-1972 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Biographical Material, 1964-1972 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Biography (for McGraw-Hill Encyclopedia of Science and Technology Supplement), 1966-1967 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Birkhoff, Garrett, 1937-1960 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Birthday--75th, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Birthday--75th, "Reminiscences on the Göttingen Math Institute", 1963 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Birthday--80th, 1967-1968, undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Bitter, Francis, 1942-1944 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Blackett, P.M.S., 1943-1951 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Blank, Albert A., 1964 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Boas, Ralph P. Jr., 1947-1952 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Bodvarsson, Gunnar, 1953-1954 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Boeing Aircraft (Dr. C.K. Stedman), undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Bohr, Aage, 1962-1969, undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Bohr, Harald, 1945-1952 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Bohr, Niels (1 of 2), 1947-1962 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Bohr, Niels (2 of 2), 1947-1962 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Bohr, Neils--Courant essay "Fifty Years of Friendship", circa 1962 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Bohr, Niels--Courant remarks at Copenhagen memorial (1 of 2), 1963 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Bohr, Niels--Courant remarks at Copenhagen memorial (2 of 2), 1963 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Bolster, Admiral C.M., 1951-1953 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Bolza, Hans, 1946-1949 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Books--General, 1943, 1965-1976 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Born, Max, 1939-1959 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Born, Max, 1961-1966 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Bouwkamp, C.J., 1952 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Bowles, Edward, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Bradley, Omar, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Brandt, Leo (1 of 2), 1955-1960 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Brandt, Leo (2 of 2), 1955-1960 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Brandt, Leo, 1961-1969 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Brandt, Leo--Arbeitsgemeinschaft für Forschung des Landes Nordrhein-Westfalen, 1957, 1963, undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Brandt, Leo--Arbeitsgemeinschaft für Forschung des Landes Nordrhein-Westfalen, 1958, 1959, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Brandt, Leo--biographical material, 1956-1958, 1963-1964, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Braun, Helene, 1946-1956 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - British Admiralty Delegation, 1943, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - British Air Commission, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - British Supply Office, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Brodsky, Ralph Howard, 1947, 1954, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Brodsky, Ruth Nanda Anshen (including World Perspectives series), 1954-1962, 1967 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Bromberg, Eleazer, 1951-1966 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Bronk, Detlev W., 1949-1960 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Bronk, Detlev W., 1961-1962 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1947-1959 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1961-1968, undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Brunauer, Stephen, 1950-1952 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1945-1959 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Burroughs Corporation, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Busemann, Herbert, 1949-1955 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - "C" Misc., 1937-1949 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - "C" Misc., 1950-1960 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - C through Cn, 1961-1970, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Co through Cz, 1961-1971 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Co through Cz, 1961-1971 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Calculus of Variations, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Calculus of Variations, 1937-1938 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Calculus of Variations--Supplementary Notes and Exercises to 1945-1946 Notes, 1949-1950 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Calendar, 1965-1967 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - California Institute of Technology, 1944-1948 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - California, University of, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - California, University of, 1954-1957 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - California, University of, 1963-1964 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - California, University of--Institute for Basic Research in Science, 1958-1959, undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Caratheodory, Stephanas, 1950, 1958 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Carbogen Corp., 1957 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Case Institute of Technology, 1953, 1958 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Cauchy's Problem, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Cesari, Lamberto, 1954-1955 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Chairman, Math Department University Heights, 1948-1949 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Challenge Magazine--Interview with Richard Courant, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Challenge Magazine--Interviews with Oskar Morgenstern, Norbert Wiener, 1959-1960 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Chandrasekhar, Subrahmanyan, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Chase, Harry Woodburn (NYU Office of the Chancellor), 1933, 1948-1966 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      Contains clippings, copy of Japanese physics journal
    - Chase, Harry Woodburn (NYU Office of the Chancellor), 1937-1941 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Chase, Harry Woodburn (NYU Office of the Chancellor), 1942-1947 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Chase, Harry Woodburn (NYU Office of the Chancellor), Charles B. Morrey (Berkeley)--Move to Berkeley, 1945-1953 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Clusius, Klaus, 1945-1949 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - College of Advanced Science, 1958, undated (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Cohn, Harvey, 1961-1963 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Colorado, University of, 1961-1962 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Complex Variable--No Errata, 1944-1945 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Computation Laboratory Project, 1944-1949 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Computer Council, 1955 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Computer Science, Stanford University Program in--George F. Forsythe, [1966] (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Computing Centers, General Problems Confronting, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Computing Center Memos, Extra Photocopies, 1952-1958 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Computing Center--Travel, 1959 February-1965 October (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Computing Machines--Germany (Report from Göttingen), 1952 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Condon, Edward U., 1941, 1951-1956 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Conference Board of Associated Research, 1953-1954 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Conference on Partial Differential Equations--University of California, 1955 June (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Congressional Record, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Conkling, Randall and David Ellis: Metric Delta Lattices, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Consulting Agreements--Argonne, 1953-1971 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Consulting Agreements--Army Ordinance Ballistic Research Labs, Maryland, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Consulting Agreements--Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Consulting Agreements--Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1961-1969 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Consulting Agreements--California, University of, Radiation Lab, 1961-1965 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Consulting Agreements--General Atomic, 1955-1960 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Consulting Agreements--General Atomic, 1961-1970 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Consulting Agreements--IBM, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Consulting Agreements--Los Alamos, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Consulting Agreements--Misc., 1941-1953 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Consulting Agreements--Misc., 1961 (Box 35, Folder 21)
    - Convair (1 of 2), 1951-1958 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Convair (2 of 2), 1951-1958 (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Convair Scientific Research Program (1 of 2), 1950-1956 undated (Box 36, Folder 1)